<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-01T18:45:34-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Diego Giacomelli</title><subtitle>programmer</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Unity and Game Development links (July 1st 2019)</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-july-1st-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unity and Game Development links (July 1st 2019)" /><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-july-1st-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-july-1st-2019/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unity&lt;/strong&gt; released a YouTube tutorial about how to create a portal effect in Lightweight Render Pipeline with Shader Graph (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TkzASwVgnj8&quot;&gt;Making Portals with Shader Graph in Unity! (Tutorial)&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dilmer Valecillos&lt;/strong&gt; posted a video on augmented reality while implementing a dragging feature with ray-casting (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nBftG-gXUE8&quot;&gt;AR Foundation with Unity3d and Adding Dragging Functionality with AR Raycast and Physics Raycast&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Felipe Lira&lt;/strong&gt; created a GitHub repository with a bare bones Scriptable Render Pipeline. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phi-lira/HelloSRP&quot;&gt;HelloSRP&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bare Bones Scriptable Render Pipeline. Use it as a base to create your own.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sebastian Lague&lt;/strong&gt; made some updates to his path creation tool (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SebLague/Path-Creator&quot;&gt;Bézier Path Creator&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;An intuitive and lightweight editor for quickly creating smooth paths in the editor.
You can easily make objects move along these paths, or use them as a guide for spawning objects and generating meshes.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unity&lt;/strong&gt;, started its annual survey asking for community feedback (&lt;a href=&quot;https://on.unity.com/2xdSRmX&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sykoo&lt;/strong&gt; published a YouTube video showing what he learned after making more than 100 game levels (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WPimiBP8d6o&quot;&gt;What I Learned after Making 100+ GAME LEVELS! (Unity Level Design)&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nichole Wong&lt;/strong&gt; wrote about the new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Unity Learn Premium&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/27/introducing-unity-learn-premium/&quot;&gt;Introducing Unity Learn Premium: Get direct guidance from experts&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;We’ve heard your requests for more advanced and in-depth content, and resources for specific industries like automotive, architecture, or media and entertainment. And we’ve also heard that you want access to experts who can give you immediate guidance and feedback on specific challenges or questions&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eduardo Oriz and Alitt Khaliq&lt;/strong&gt; made a post showing the behind the scenes and dive further into the creative process behind Buried Memories Volume 2: Serekh (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/28/the-creative-process-behind-serekh/&quot;&gt;The creative process behind Serekh&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Developing a strong game, large or small, depends on having a dedicated team of skilled and specialized people who share a vision and care deeply about what they are making. The development of Serekh was a combined effort by Edvige Faini, the Concept Artist, and the Unity Icon Collective. Some of the most significant challenges on this project were conceptual rather than technical.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sykoo&lt;/strong&gt; again, with a video on tips, tricks, and list of features in Unity for making 2D games (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-MuWAydTjY0&quot;&gt;How to make 2D Games with Unity 2019!&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="gamedev" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting an Unity3D project with GeneticSharp using dotnet new</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/starting-an-unity3d-project-with-geneticsharp-using-dotnet-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting an Unity3D project with GeneticSharp using dotnet new" /><published>2019-06-27T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-27T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/starting-an-unity3d-project-with-geneticsharp-using-dotnet-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/starting-an-unity3d-project-with-geneticsharp-using-dotnet-new/">&lt;p&gt;In this post I will show how to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dotnet new&lt;/code&gt; command to start an Unity3D project with GeneticSharp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime ago I created a NuGet package called &lt;a href=&quot;/dotnet-new-templates-for-GeneticSharp&quot;&gt;GeneticSharp.Templates&lt;/a&gt;, this package allows developers to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/giacomelli/GeneticSharp&quot;&gt;GeneticSharp&lt;/a&gt; templates using the dotnet new command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the availables templates in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GeneticSharp.Templates&lt;/code&gt;, there is one specific to create an Unity3D project with GeneticSharp. Besides this, the project has a sample of Travelling Salesman Problem (TSP) using GeneticSharp and can be used as a scaffold to starting use genetic algorithms in your games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create an Unity3D project using dotnet new is fast and simple, depending of your machine performance, you’ll have the sample running in less than a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal/prompt and type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dotnet new &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-i&lt;/span&gt; GeneticSharp.Templates
dotnet new GeneticSharpTspUnity3d &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; GeneticSharpSample
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic; font-size:small&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The argument &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/code&gt; is the the output folder of the Unity3D project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can open the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GeneticSharpSample&lt;/code&gt; in Unity3D editor.
Open the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MainScene&lt;/code&gt; scene and hit the play button, you should see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/2019/06/27/starting-an-unity3d-project-with-geneticsharp-using-dotnet-new/geneticsharp-ts-template.gif &quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats it, now you can use this sample to understand how to use GeneticSharp in your game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more details about the code and the sample itself, please, take a look on this tutorial &lt;a href=&quot;/tsp-with-GeneticSharp-and-Unity3d/&quot;&gt;TSP with GeneticSharp and Unity3D&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you need an introduction to genetic algorithms, this tutorial could help you &lt;a href=&quot;/function-optimization-with-geneticsharp/&quot;&gt;Function optimization with GeneticSharp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s evolve!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="geneticsharp" /><category term="unity3d" /><category term="dotnet" /><summary type="html">In this post I will show how to use dotnet new command to start an Unity3D project with GeneticSharp. Introduction Sometime ago I created a NuGet package called GeneticSharp.Templates, this package allows developers to install GeneticSharp templates using the dotnet new command.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">unitytips&amp;amp;colon; Gist Importer</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-gist-importer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="unitytips&amp;colon; Gist Importer" /><published>2019-06-25T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-gist-importer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-gist-importer/">&lt;p&gt;Using the Gist below you can easily import other Gists to your Unity project just copying the URL from browser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YljjAkebxiE &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/9a248eecf5c1ffc477b59524f63264d3.js&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic; font-size:small&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All Gists are imported to folder &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Assets/Gists&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="unitytips" /><category term="gamedev" /><summary type="html">Using the Gist below you can easily import other Gists to your Unity project just copying the URL from browser:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unity and Game Development links (June 24th 2019)</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-june-24th-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unity and Game Development links (June 24th 2019)" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-june-24th-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-june-24th-2019/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sykoo&lt;/strong&gt; made a video about the Buried Memories Volume 2: Serekh (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5CTAVFOrbsM&quot;&gt;Buried Memories: Serekh – New HDRP Asset Pack for Unity! (Overview)&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Christophe Cimetiere&lt;/strong&gt; wrote a post about how to use Unity as a library inside other apps (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/17/add-features-powered-by-unity-to-native-mobile-apps&quot;&gt;Add features powered by Unity to native mobile apps&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unity 2019.3 will add support for using Unity as a library controlled by native Android/Java and iOS/Objective C apps so you can easily insert AR and other Unity features.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egor Bogatov&lt;/strong&gt; created a GitHub repository with a sample Xamarin app using Unity as a library (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/EgorBo/XamarinWithUnityApp&quot;&gt;XamarinWithUnityApp&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You can now easily add a Unity scene (e.g. ARCore scene) to any native or Xamarin app via .aar file.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jacob Shriar&lt;/strong&gt; posted about a survey that Unity made with 1000 creatives within advertising and marketing about AR (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/18/creative-professionals-are-struggling-to-implement-augmented-reality&quot;&gt;Creative professionals are struggling to implement augmented reality&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In anticipation for Cannes this year, we surveyed 1000 creatives within advertising and marketing to gauge a better understanding on their comfort level, technical competency, and enthusiasm towards AR, including what it means for the future of storytelling. And what we found was very telling&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harry Alisavakis&lt;/strong&gt;, released another tutorial in his series &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;VFX Master Shader&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://halisavakis.com/my-take-on-shaders-vfx-master-shader-part-ii/&quot;&gt;My take on shaders: VFX Master Shader (Part II)&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Davis&lt;/strong&gt; wrote about how automotive companies are leveraging real-time 3D to reduce costs and accelerate development (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/19/how-real-time-3d-is-changing-every-industry&quot;&gt;How real-time 3D is changing every industry&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Real-time 3D is changing everything, in much deeper ways than most people realize. Forged in gaming, this technology continues to transform the way games are created, operated and monetized. Its impact now also extends to industries of all kinds, from film to automotive.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Barton&lt;/strong&gt; made a post about how HDRP is taking next-gen graphics to a new level (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcvuk.com/in-the-pipeline-unitys-hdrp-brings-next-gen-graphics-to-the-worlds-most-used-game-engine/&quot;&gt;In the pipeline: Unity’s HDRP brings next-gen graphics to the world’s most-used game engine&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;What do System Shock 3, Oddworld: Soulstorm and Harold Halibut have in common? Well, all of these incredible-looking upcoming titles are built on Unity, and more specifically will utilise Unity’s upcoming High Definition Render Pipeline or HDRP for short.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caitlin W and Macy Mills&lt;/strong&gt; wrote a post about the new Unity’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Verified Solutions Partners&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/20/unitys-new-partnerships-bring-verified-solutions-to-developers-across-industries&quot;&gt;Unity’s new partnerships bring verified solutions to developers across industries&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Verified Solutions Partners represent a collection of 3rd-party SDKs, plugins, editor applications, cloud services, and more that enable the success of your project while ensuring deeper technical alignment with partners’ products and services to ensure 0% developer downtime. Partners accepted into the program go through a verification process to ensure their SDK or software is optimized for the latest version of Unity.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elena Nizhnik&lt;/strong&gt; released a new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Community Component&lt;/code&gt; post, highlighting some games, posts, videos and tools (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/22/community-component-audio-design-pixel-games-custom-tools-and-best-of-made-with-unity-on-youtube&quot;&gt;Community Component – audio design, pixel games, custom tools and Best of Made with Unity on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sykoo&lt;/strong&gt; again, now with a timelapse level design video (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3vNNUC1tnE&quot;&gt;LEVEL DESIGN IN UNITY! - Village &amp;amp; Castle Scene (Timelapse)&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brackeys&lt;/strong&gt; made a video about the new Terrain System in Unity (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MWQv2Bagwgk&quot;&gt;How to make Terrain in Unity!&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="gamedev" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GeneticSharp in the Wild&amp;amp;colon; Context-Sensitive Code Completion</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/geneticsharp-in-the-wild-context-sensitive-code-completion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GeneticSharp in the Wild&amp;colon; Context-Sensitive Code Completion" /><published>2019-06-21T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-21T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/geneticsharp-in-the-wild-context-sensitive-code-completion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/geneticsharp-in-the-wild-context-sensitive-code-completion/">&lt;p&gt;I decided to start a &lt;a href=&quot;/tags/geneticsharp-in-the-wild/&quot;&gt;series of posts&lt;/a&gt; about some outstanding scientific papers and projects using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/giacomelli/GeneticSharp&quot;&gt;GeneticSharp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this second post the choose one is the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Context-Sensitive Code
Completion: Improving Predictions with Genetic Algorithms&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main motivation of the author about this paper was:
&lt;em&gt;Current methods of training code completion systems can possibly be improved in order
to reduce prediction errors. This requires that the amount of information considered in a
pattern is optimized. The question raised is then: how should the training of predictive
models be focused in order to increase prediction quality?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This thesis will aim to answer the question: to what extent is it possible to improve predictions
of existing state-of-the-art code completion systems with a genetic algorithm?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GeneticSharp is an open-source Genetic Algorithm library for C#, released under the MIT
license (Giacomelli). It has an extensible interface that allows for most, if not all, functionality
to be implemented from scratch via interfaces or leveraged by extending base classes. Classes
and interfaces also use the same terminology that has already been established, which makes
the translation from theory to implementation much more clear.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a result of the new training scheme, the quality of predictions can be increased without
losing generalizability. Application of the new training scheme could possibly be applied
to any code completion systems that trains a predictive model, making it a candidate for
improving existing systems as well as in future research.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/2019/06/21/geneticsharp-in-the-wild-context-sensitive-code-completion/gscc-vs-genecscc.png &quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic; font-size:small&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;results comparison between GCC and GeneCSCC (developed using GeneticSharp)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Author&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcus Ording wrote the paper for his degree project in Computer Engineering at KTH Royal Institute of Technology from Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can access the full paper directly on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diva-portal.org/smash/get/diva2:1088591/FULLTEXT01.pdf&quot;&gt;DiVA Portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="geneticsharp" /><category term="geneticsharp-in-the-wild" /><summary type="html">I decided to start a series of posts about some outstanding scientific papers and projects using GeneticSharp.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">unitytips&amp;amp;colon; Changing the style of the Hierarchy Window Group Header</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-changing-the-style-of-the-hierarchy-window-group-header/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="unitytips&amp;colon; Changing the style of the Hierarchy Window Group Header" /><published>2019-06-20T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-20T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-changing-the-style-of-the-hierarchy-window-group-header</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-changing-the-style-of-the-hierarchy-window-group-header/">&lt;p&gt;In my last &lt;a href=&quot;/tags/unitytips/&quot;&gt;#unitytips&lt;/a&gt; I demonstrated how you could create a visual header to any group of components on your hierarchy window using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;EditorApplication.hierarchyWindowItemOnGUI&lt;/code&gt;. Now I’m improving it allowing you to &lt;strong&gt;customize its style&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g2lq0lIJzh8 &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic; font-size:small&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To change the style, you just need to edit the values of the HierarchyWindowGroupHeaderSettings in the inspector&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/bb6a9932e5f49a072c57a7c17135bf6b.js?file=HierarchyWindowGroupHeader.cs&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember that you need to save the above .cs inside any &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Editor&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a good practice add the tag &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;EditorOnly&lt;/code&gt; to your group header game objects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="unitytips" /><category term="gamedev" /><category term="hierarchy-window" /><summary type="html">In my last #unitytips I demonstrated how you could create a visual header to any group of components on your hierarchy window using EditorApplication.hierarchyWindowItemOnGUI. Now I’m improving it allowing you to customize its style.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">unitytips&amp;amp;colon; Hierarchy Window Group Header</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-hierarchy-window-group-header/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="unitytips&amp;colon; Hierarchy Window Group Header" /><published>2019-06-18T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-hierarchy-window-group-header</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-hierarchy-window-group-header/">&lt;p&gt;You can create a visual header to any group of components on your hierarchy window using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;EditorApplication.hierarchyWindowItemOnGUI&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YS5H8Y2Ytww &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/35410d682e41a504c7869a464a96c30a.js?file=HierarchyWindowGroupHeader.cs&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic; font-size:small&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any GameObject with name that starts with “—” will be considered a group header&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="unitytips" /><category term="gamedev" /><category term="hierarchy-window" /><summary type="html">You can create a visual header to any group of components on your hierarchy window using EditorApplication.hierarchyWindowItemOnGUI:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unity and Game Development links (June 17th 2019)</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-june-17th-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unity and Game Development links (June 17th 2019)" /><published>2019-06-17T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-17T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-june-17th-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unity-and-gamedev-links-june-17th-2019/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sebastian Lague&lt;/strong&gt; made an ecosystem simulation with foxes and rabbits in Unity3d (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r_It_X7v-1E&quot;&gt;Coding Adventure: Simulating an Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marius Horga&lt;/strong&gt; wrote an overview about Metal 3 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://metalkit.org/2019/06/10/introducing-metal-3.html&quot;&gt;Introducing Metal 3&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Metal 3 was announced last week at WWDC 2019. Apple presented it along with relevant numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Metal can now make 100 times more draw calls than OpenGL.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Metal runs on roughly 1.4 billion devices currently.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Metal can drive up to 56 TFLOPS of single precision.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mike Wuetherick&lt;/strong&gt;, Head of Tech for Unity’s Innovation Group, posted about “Sherman”, the new short film made in real-time using Unity (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/11/introducing-sherman-part-1&quot;&gt;Introducing Sherman (Part 1) – a Unity project featuring Real time fur, HDRP and Visual FX Graph for animators&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Created by the Emmy-winning team that brought you Baymax Dreams, Sherman is a new real time Unity short that delivers the most advanced real time fur ever!&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brandi House&lt;/strong&gt; posted a guidance to transition the games between UNet and the new connected games stack (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.unity3d.com/2019/06/13/navigating-unitys-multiplayer-netcode-transition&quot;&gt;Navigating Unity’s multiplayer Netcode transition&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As many of you know, we put UNet into maintenance mode because we believe there is a better way forward with our new connected games stack&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;War Robots case study&lt;/strong&gt; shows how Pixonic used Unity to lift up their revenue from War Robots without negatively impacting user experience (&lt;a href=&quot;https://unity.com/case-study/pixonic-war-robots&quot;&gt;Pixonic - War Robots case study&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;How do you find new revenue opportunities in a free-to-play game that’s been going strong for over five years? Moscow-based Pixonic, a Top 100-grossing game developer in the CIS, has driven War Robots’ monthly players’ spending to over $5M.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keijiro Takahashi&lt;/strong&gt;, an Unity evangelist, released the first version of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MidiAnimationTrack&lt;/code&gt; that imports .mid files into Unity Timeline. It allows creating musically synchronized animation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/keijiro/MidiAnimationTrack&quot;&gt;MIDI Animation Track&lt;/a&gt;).
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Is a custom timeline/playables package that provides functionality to control object properties based on sequence data contained in a standard MIDI file&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sykoo&lt;/strong&gt; made a new video about his 5 favorite assets from Unity Asset Store (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LLlJzQNYsAI&quot;&gt;5 AMAZING ASSETS for Unity 2019&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brackeys&lt;/strong&gt; released a video about new 2D renderer in Unity (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nkgGyO9VG54&quot;&gt;2D Lights in Unity!&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="gamedev" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Tesseract 4 with C#</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/using-tesseract4-with-csharp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Tesseract 4 with C#" /><published>2019-06-13T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-13T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/using-tesseract4-with-csharp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/using-tesseract4-with-csharp/">&lt;p&gt;Recently I built a small tool to read the text of thousands of images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common technique to extract text from images is know as OCR (Optical character recognition) and the best implementation, that I Know, is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract&quot;&gt;Tesseract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a I started to build the tool, I used the most famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/charlesw/tesseract&quot;&gt;Tesseract’s wrapper for .NET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the wrapper worked very well, I was curious about if there was a way to get better peformance results. With a little search I noticed that the .NET wrapper still use Tesseract 3, but there was a version 4 available with a lot of performance improvements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are running Tesseract 4, you can use the “fast” integer models.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tesseract 4 also uses up to four CPU threads while processing a page, so it will be faster than Tesseract 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style:italic; font-size:small&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract/wiki/FAQ#can-i-increase-speed-of-ocr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to try Tesseract 4 to see how could it impact in the performance of my tool. As at the time there was no .NET wrapper for it, I removed the old wrapper and called Tesseract 4 directly as a process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The use of Tesseract 4 cut off the time to read the images in almost half&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tesseractservice&quot;&gt;TesseractService&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up developing the class below to call the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Tesseract 4&lt;/code&gt; command-line &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(tesseract.exe)&lt;/code&gt; directly from the C# code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/ae80c1ed9b374894b21890f1d2dee42a.js?file=TesseractService.cs&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;setup&quot;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just download the gist above and add it to your .NET project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Tesseract 4
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Linux and OSX: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract/wiki&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Windows: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UB-Mannheim/tesseract/wiki&quot;&gt;https://github.com/UB-Mannheim/tesseract/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the trained data model for the language you need to read the images
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More accurate, but slower: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tessdata_best&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tessdata_best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Faster, but less accurate: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tessdata_fast&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tessdata_fast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/ae80c1ed9b374894b21890f1d2dee42a.js?file=usage-sample.cs&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try to read a image like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/2019/06/13/using-tesseract4-with-csharp/input-sample-image.png &quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will get this result after call the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TesseractService.GetText&lt;/code&gt; method:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The (quick) [brown] {fox} jumps!
Over the $43,456.78 &amp;lt;lazy&amp;gt; #90 dog
&amp;amp; duck/goose, as 12.5% of E-mail
from aspammer@website.com is spam.
Der ,.schnelle&quot; braune Fuchs springt
iiber den faulen Hund. Le renard brun
«rapide» saute par-dessus le chien
paresseux. La volpe marrone rapida
salta sopra il cane pigro. El zorro
marron rapido salta sobre el perro
perezoso. A raposa marrom rapida
salta sobre o céo preguicoso.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/charlesw/tesseract&quot;&gt;A .Net wrapper for tesseract-ocr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract/wiki/FAQ#can-i-increase-speed-of-ocr&quot;&gt;Can I increase speed of OCR?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/doxakis/How-to-use-tesseract-ocr-4.0-with-csharp&quot;&gt;How to use Tesseract OCR 4.0 with C#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://appliedmachinelearning.blog/2018/06/30/performing-ocr-by-running-parallel-instances-of-tesseract-4-0-python/&quot;&gt;Performing OCR by running parallel instances of Tesseract 4.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract&quot;&gt;Tesseract repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tesseract" /><category term="ocr" /><category term="dotnet" /><summary type="html">Recently I built a small tool to read the text of thousands of images.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">unitytips&amp;amp;colon; MenuItem “CONTEXT/component”</title><link href="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-menuitem-context-component/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="unitytips&amp;colon; MenuItem &quot;CONTEXT/component&quot;" /><published>2019-06-11T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-06-11T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-menuitem-context-component</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://diegogiacomelli.com.br/unitytips-menuitem-context-component/">&lt;p&gt;You can create a context menu for any component using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;CONTEXT/&amp;lt;component&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;menu name&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; on a MenuItem attribute:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZCGsunoO-TA &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;pre&gt;400: Invalid request
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/3c05b37b9af2ec6cfef0db58a2e5e3a7.js?file=TransformContextMenu.cs&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unity3d" /><category term="unitytips" /><category term="gamedev" /><summary type="html">You can create a context menu for any component using the &quot;CONTEXT/&amp;lt;component&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;menu name&amp;gt;&quot; on a MenuItem attribute:</summary></entry></feed>