<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Diego Giacomelli - game-jam</title>
 <link href="//tags/game-jam/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/tag/game-jam.html"/>
 <updated>2020-09-17T12:34:30-03:00</updated>
 <id>/tag/game-jam.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Diego Giacomelli</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kenney Jam 2020 entry&colon; Curseings</title>
   <link href="//keeney-jam-2020-entry-curseings/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
   <id>//keeney-jam-2020-entry-curseings</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I participated in &lt;strong&gt;Kenney Jam 2020&lt;/strong&gt; (my first game jam).
The experience was really good, when you have so strong boundaries to make a game, in this case, &lt;strong&gt;48 hours and just use assets from &lt;a href=&quot;http://Kenney.nl/assets&quot;&gt;Kenney&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, you need to turn your way of think and expectations to a very specific and clear objective: release a fun and playable game the target just the core mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-theme&quot;&gt;The theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme for this game jam was &lt;strong&gt;“Cursed”&lt;/strong&gt;.
I took some time thinking about what game I would like to play and develop with such a theme, then I remembered how much I loved to play Lemmings and how those little ones were cursed to live in the small world where some of them should sacrifice for the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, I started developing the game and things happened very well and I delivered my entry right on time. I had the finished version some hours before, but I took some time to review it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final result is &lt;strong&gt;a simple game that takes the Lemmings core mechanic and adds some twist&lt;/strong&gt;: in Curseings, there are two kinds of walkers: the human and the cursed and you need to take each kind to different portals. If a cursed touch a human, that human becomes a cursed one too. The gamer will need to use this new mechanic to overcome some levels, sometimes the player will need to avoid they touch each other, sometimes don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I3fRyrc6yrA &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
      &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-play&quot;&gt;How to play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game can be download for Windows and Mac here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://giacomelli.itch.io/curseings&quot;&gt;https://giacomelli.itch.io/curseings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just drag a behavior from the toolbar over a correspond walker to change his behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The objective of each level is to help the expected number of people and cursed to reach each portal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When a cursed touches a person, the person morphs into a cursed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drag an item from the toolbar over a person or cursed to change its behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;                
        &lt;picture&gt;
  &lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 900px) 80vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/generated/assets/2020/08/26/keeney-jam-2020-entry-curseings/cast-a-vote-192-6b3e9fff4.webp 192w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 900px) 80vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/generated/assets/2020/08/26/keeney-jam-2020-entry-curseings/cast-a-vote-192-6b3e9fff4.png 192w&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;screenshot&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/generated/assets/2020/08/26/keeney-jam-2020-entry-curseings/cast-a-vote-192-6b3e9fff4.png&quot; width=&quot;192&quot; height=&quot;256&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

      &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-vote&quot;&gt;How to vote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you liked the game, &lt;strong&gt;you can cast a vote&lt;/strong&gt; for the game jam here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/jam/kenney-jam-2020/rate/737655&quot;&gt;https://itch.io/jam/kenney-jam-2020/rate/737655&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>